Previously on the show.
Episode sebelumnya.
Wolffy also attended the farewell party organized
Wolffy menghadiri pesta perpisahan
But his scheme failed.
Tapi rencananya gagal.
Amid the farewell fireworks the seven colored beans lit,
Saat kembang api perpisahan dinyalakan,
the goats headed towards a new destination.
para kambing menuju ke tujuan baru.
What new challenges are they going to face?
Tantangan baru apa yang akan mereka hadapi?
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Balloon City Amid The Storm."
Petualangan Langit Pulau Terbang: Kota Balon Di Tengah Badai.
The weather doesn’t look good today.
Cuacanya tak bagus hari ini.
I think a storm is coming. Should we find a place to take shelter?
Kurasa badai akan datang. Apa perlu cari tempat berlindung?
But the radar indicates that our buddy is right ahead.
Tapi radar menunjukkan bahwa teman kita ada di depan.
Let's just hurry over.
Kita harus cepat ke sana.
Hello, little goats.
Halo, Kambing.
Why is it Wolffy again?
Kenapa ada Wolffy lagi?
You can't escape this time.
Kau tak bisa lolos kali ini.
Let me deal with Wolffy.
Biar kuurus Wolffy.
Let’s dance, Wolffy.
Mari menari, Wolffy.
I will be fine as long as I put the headphones on.
Aku aman selama pakai fon telinga.
Wolffy.
Wolffy.
Oh, why am I dancing? Wolffy, help me. I want to stop.
Kenapa aku menari? Wolffy, tolong. Aku mau berhenti.
Oh no, not again!
Tidak, jangan lagi!
Tibbie, you are awesome.
Tibbie, kau hebat.
You flatter me...
Aku jadi malu...
Why do I feel like Magic Train is moving?
Kenapa aku merasa Kereta Ajaib bergerak?
-What?
- Apa?
Oh no, it’s the storm.
Tidak, ini badainya.
We'll be sucked into it.
Kita akan tersedot masuk!
Oh no...
Tidak...
Why am I also sucked into it?
Kenapa aku juga ikut tersedot?
We can't let this continue. We have to break through it.
Ini tak bisa terus terjadi. Kita harus melewatinya.
Look. There's light on this side.
Lihat. Ada cahaya di sisi ini.
That should be the way out.
Itu jalan keluar!
Phew! Guys, are you all right?
Kalian baik-baik saja?
I'm fine.
Aku baik.
Weslie, look.
Weslie, lihat.
There's a city in the middle of the storm.
Ada kota di tengah badai.
That must be where our buddy is.
Itu pasti lokasi teman kita.
Let’s go there now.
Ayo ke sana.
Oh, Weslie, Tibbie, come out now!
Weslie, Tibbie, keluarlah!
Look, there are balloons everywhere.
Astaga, ada balon di mana-mana.
It's such a colorful and beautiful place.
Ini tempat yang penuh warna dan indah.
Wow, even the ground is soft.
Wah, tanahnya empuk.
These flowers are all made of balloons.
Semua bunga terbuat dari balon.
Weslie.
Weslie.
Look, these balloon flowers are so beautiful.
Lihat, bunga balon ini sangat indah.
Hey!
Hei!
Why did you pick me up?
Kenapa kau mengangkatku?
Nothing...
Tidak ada...
You're odd.
Dasar aneh.
I didn’t expect the citizens to be balloons too.
Tak kusangka warganya juga balon.
Oh no, this is terrible. Guys, come check this out.
Astaga, ini gawat. Hei, lihat ini.
-What is it? -Look.
- Ada apa? - Lihat.
-Sparky?
Sparky?
This isn’t the only wanted notice. It's posted everywhere.
Posternya bukan ini saja. Ada banyak!
Why is Sparky wanted?
Kenapa Sparky buron?
Weslie, what should we do now?
Kini kita harus bagaimana?
Let’s go back first.
Kembali. Lebih mudah mencarinya dengan Kereta Ajaib.
Sir, we suspect that Sparky is hiding inside this unidentified flying object.
Pak, kami curiga Sparky sembunyi di dalam benda terbang asing ini.
Let’s go in and search immediately then.
Mari segera kita periksa.
They're trying to arrest Sparky?
Mereka mau menahan Sparky?
Why do they look so familiar?
Kenapa mereka tampak tak asing?
White hair, horns on their heads.
Rambut putih, tanduk di kepala.
I got it. They are Sparky’s fellow mates.
Aku tahu. Mereka teman Sparky!
Hurry, take them back now.
Cepat, tahan mereka sekarang.
Oh no, run!
Tidak, lari!
Stop!
Berhenti!
Wolnie, son, where are you two?
Wolnie, anakku, kalian di mana?
It's a dead end. What should we do?
Jalan buntu. Kini bagaimana?
There's a gap between the balloon walls. Let’s hide inside.
Ada celah di antara dinding. Sembunyi di dalam.
Oh no, I’m stuck.
Aku terjebak!
How come they've disappeared? Let’s split up and find them.
Mana mereka? Berpencar dan cari mereka.
Yes, sir.
Ya, Pak.
The soldiers left.
- Para prajurit pergi. - Weslie?
Sparky!
Sparky!
Guys.
Teman-teman.
-Sparky! -Are you guys all right?
- Sparky! - Kalian tak apa-apa?
There's a storm outside. How did you get in?
Ada badai di luar. Bagaimana bisa masuk?
Calm down, Sparky. The new Magic Train brought us here.
Tenang, Sparky. Kereta Ajaib baru membawa kami kemari.
The new Magic Train?
Kereta Ajaib baru?
Yes, the new Magic Train was constructed by a mechanical expert
Ya, Kereta Ajaib baru yang dibangun oleh ahli mekanik
whom I met in Tower Town.
yang kutemui di Kota Menara.
That is wonderful. With a new Magic Train...
Hebat! Dengan Kereta Ajaib baru...
He isn’t listening to me at all.
Dia mengacuhkanku.
I think I hear Sparky's voice from there. Let’s go check it out.
Aku dengar suara Sparky dari sana. Ayo periksa.
Let’s leave quickly. Otherwise, they'll take me back to General Balloon.
Ayo pergi. Jika tidak, aku akan dibawa ke Jenderal Balon.
-Wait for me! -Where're we going?
- Tunggu! - Kita ke mana?
To look for the Magic Train of course.
Jelas mencari Kereta Ajaib.
They would surely send a big flying object like the Magic Train
Objek terbang besar seperti Kereta Ajaib pasti dibawa ke gudang barang berbahaya.
We have to stop them before it gets there.
Kita harus cegat sebelum tiba.
But Sparky, why do they want to arrest you?
Tapi Sparky, kenapa mereka mau menangkapmu?
It's a long story.
Ceritanya panjang.
After the explosion that day,
Setelah ledakan hari itu,
I was pushed towards this storm.
aku masuk ke badai ini.
What is this place?
Tempat apa ini?
Oh, he has horns.
Dia punya tanduk!
Wait.
Tunggu.
Don’t move.
Jangan bergerak.
The balloons are afraid of sharp things.
Balon takut pada benda tajam.
The soldiers surrounded me immediately.
Para prajurit segera mengepungku.
Everybody, don’t be afraid.
Jangan takut.
My horns are rounded. Look, they aren’t dangerous.
Tandukku bulat. Mereka tak berbahaya.
Oh, that is so scary! He poked the tree.
Menakutkan sekali.  Dia menusuk pohonnya.
No wonder they also want to arrest us. It's because of these horns.
Pantas mereka juga mau menangkap kita, karena tanduk ini.
All clear. Let’s go.
Semua aman. Ayo.
Sparky.
Sparky.
What? Run!
Apa? Lari!
Stop running.
Jangan lari.
They're chasing us. What should we do?
Kita dikejar. Bagaimana ini?
Let’s hide inside the rubbish bin. What?
Sembunyi di tempat sampah. Apa?
What? Where did they go?
Apa? Ke mana mereka?
Let’s check over there.
Ayo cari di sana.
Why are you here?
Kenapa kau di sini?
How dare you ask me that?
Beraninya kau bertanya begitu.
Oh no, why are we sucked into it as well?
Tidak, kenapa kita tersedot juga?
If not for you guys,
Jika bukan karena kalian, aku dan keluargaku takkan tiba di sini!
When I was looking for Sirius to leave this place,
Saat mencari Sirius untuk meninggalkan tempat ini,
a group of balloon soldiers appeared.
sekelompok prajurit balon muncul.
-Just like that. -Look, it is that wolf.
- Lalu, - Serigala.
-I became wanted for no reason. -Take him back.
- aku menjadi buronan tanpa alasan. - Tahan dia.
What… What's going on?
Ada apa ini?
-Why are you chasing after me? -Stop...
- Kenapa mengejar? - Berhenti!
I wonder how Wolnie and Willie are doing now.
Aku mau tahu bagaimana keadaan Wolnie dan Willie.
Where can I find them?
Di mana mereka berada?
I suppose Sirius has also been taken
Kurasa Sirius juga dibawa ke gudang barang berbahaya oleh balon.
Dangerous goods warehouse? How dangerous can that be?
Gudang barang berbahaya? Seberapa berbahaya itu?
Wolffy, calm down.
Wolffy, tenanglah.
Let’s get the Magic Train and Sirius back together.
Mari dapatkan Kereta Ajaib dan Sirius kembali bersama.
What are we waiting for then? We...
Apa yang kita tunggu? Kita...
-Stop! -Run!
- Lari! - Stop!
It’s Sparky and that grey fellow.
Itu Sparky dan pria abu-abunya.
Capture them now.
Tangkap mereka!
Intercept Sparky and that grey fellow!
Cegat Sparky dan pria abu-abu itu!
Look. Magic Train is right there.
Lihat. Itu Kereta Ajaibnya.
Where is Sirius then?
Di mana Sirius?
I have no idea either.
Aku juga tidak tahu.
What?
Apa?
I’ll take another route. Nothing goes well when I'm with you.
Aku ambil rute lain. Tak ada yang baik saat bersamamu.
We've finally caught you.
Akhirnya kau tertangkap.
Wolffy disappeared right after we turned around.
Wolffy hilang tepat setelah kita berbalik.
I hope he didn't get caught.
Semoga dia tak tertangkap.
Move it. Split into two teams and surround them from both sides.
Cepat. Bagi jadi dua tim dan kepung dari kedua sisi.
-They can't escape then. -Yes, sir.
- Mereka tak bisa kabur. - Ya, Pak.
What is going on? Why has Wolffy suddenly become the balloons' leader?
Ada apa? Kenapa Wolffy tiba-tiba menjadi pemimpin balon?
Friends, I'm really trying to help you capture the goats.
Teman-teman, aku akan bantu menangkap kambing.
Can you untie me first?
Bisa lepaskan aku dulu?
No way. You are wanted by us.
Tak mungkin. Kau buronan kami.
They won't be able to escape.
Mereka tak bisa kabur
Oh no!
Tidak!
I'll divert them.
Biar kualihkan! Cepat naik Kereta Ajaib.
Hey, come catch me.
Coba tangkap aku!
Let's get on the Magic Train now.
Ayo naik Kereta Ajaib!
Stop!
Berhenti!
You can't get away.
Kau tak bisa kabur.
Don't run!
Jangan lari!
Sparky, come aboard now.
Sparky, cepat naik!
Don't let them get away. Toss me over there now.
Jangan biarkan mereka lolos. Lempar aku ke sana.
All right.
Baiklah.
Why didn't you untie me before tossing me?
Kenapa aku masih diikat?
We can finally leave this place.
Akhirnya kita bisa pergi!
Let's go!
Ayo!
Oh no!
Tidak!
The storm is too powerful. We can't break through at all.
Badainya terlalu kuat! Tak bisa ditembus.
General Balloon, they're back.
Jenderal Balon, mereka kembali.
General Balloon.
Jenderal Balon.
Sparky... are you injured?
Sparky....
You forced me to post posters everywhere to bring you home.
Aku sampai pasang poster agar kau pulang.
-What?
- Apa?
This isn't a wanted notice but a missing person notice?
Ini poster orang hilang, bukan buron?
Yes. Sparky is my good friend. Why would I want him arrested?
Ya. Sparky adalah temanku. Kenapa aku mau dia ditahan?
He didn't cause a commotion when he first got here?
Dia tak berbuat onar saat pertama tiba di sini?
He did cause a commotion when he first came to Balloon City.
Dia memang berbuat onar saat tiba di Kota Balon.
I really won't harm you.
Aku tak berbahaya.
Don't move.
- Jangan bergerak. - Tolong!
Help!
Tolong!
-Mom. -My child.
- Ibu. - Anakku.
General Balloon, you're here.
Jenderal Balon, kau tiba.
Are you the one? What is your name?
Apa kau orangnya? Siapa namamu?
Sparky.
Sparky.
Hey. Way to go!
Hei. Kerja bagus!
Sparky, I saw your heroic act just now.
Sparky, aku lihat aksi pahlawanmu tadi.
From now on, you are a good friend of Balloon City.
Mulai sekarang, kau sahabat Kota Balon.
-I see.
Rupanya begitu.
I didn't expect your friends to misunderstand.
Aku tak mengira temanmu salah paham.
Come. Since your friends are here,
Ayo. Karena teman-temanmu di sini,
let's go back and celebrate with a feast.
mari kembali dan rayakan dengan pesta.
Oh, there's delicious food. Let's go!
Makanan enak. Ayo!
You ended up getting caught too.
Rupanya kau tertangkap juga.
Are you friends with them?
Apa kau temannya?
No, no, no... I don't know them at all.
Tidak. Aku tak kenal mereka.
Okay, that's great. Take him to prison.
Bagus. Bawa dia ke penjara.
I'm a good guy. Why am I going to prison? Wait...
Aku orang baik. Kenapa dipenjara? Tunggu...